Curriculum Vitae

Name Nhien Thuy Phan Nguyen Email nptnhien.duoc16@ump.edu.vn

Date of birth 22nd December 1998 Phone +84 85 400 2212

Pronoun she/her/hers Website https://thuynhiennguyenphan.netlify.app/

Summary

I hold a bachelor's degree in Pharmacy in 2021 and currently serve as a researcher in the Department of Pharmaceutical Administration at the University of Medicine and Pharmacy in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. With five years of expertise in data analysis using STATA and R, alongside qualitative and quantitative analysis, my research interests include Health Economic Modelling, Health Technology Assessment, and the Antibiotic Stewardship Program (ASP), with a focus on evaluating healthcare interventions and optimizing resource allocation to improve public health outcomes. Eager to learn, share knowledge, and uphold a strong sense of responsibility, I am pursuing an academic career.

Education

| 2016 - 2021 | Pharmacist University of Medicine And Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam |
|-------------|--|
| | Specialty: Pharmaceutical Administration – GPA: 2.88/4.0 Graduation thesis: Assessment on antibiotic use in Hospital for Tropical Disease and Thong Nhat Hospital from 2017 to 2020 by antimicrobial stewardship metrics (Grade: 10.0/10.0, Supervisor: Nguyen Thi Hai Yen, PhD in Public Health) |
| March 2023 | Short course training: Understanding the entire investment lifecycle - from scientific innovation to market impact of pharmaceutical and healthcare startups Funded Visiting Scholarship by SM-Sino Technology Investment |

Research Experience

| Research Experience | | |
|----------------------------|--|--|
| May 2023 - Present | Researcher Department of Pharmaceutical Administration, University of Medicine And Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam | |
| | Performing data analysis, writing and revising research manuscripts Collaborating with principal supervisors to guide five students through undergraduate dissertations (Infectious Diseases, Drug Utilization, and Health Technology Assessment Topics) Developing standard operating procedures and automation tools for hospital data pooling, cleaning, and analysis using R and Stata Teaching knowledge and hands-on training for 20 students in health economics Contributing to designing teaching sessions and preparing materials on Pharmaceutical Legislation for undergraduate programs Conducting economic evaluation studies of Pfizer, AstraZeneca, and Merck products, including developing HECON models using VBA and R, disseminating research findings, writing reports, preparing materials for the conferences Hands-on training in health technology assessment for Eisai employees | |
| April 2022 – April 2023 | Health Technology Assessment (HTA) Executive | |
| | HORUS Company Limited, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam | |
| | Conducted economic evaluation studies of Roche and AstraZeneca products Planned and calculated for Patient Access Scheme (PAS) Scenarios to gain patient access to anticancer treatments Trained in Good Clinical Practice and clinical trial monitoring process Prepared bidding documents for health technology assessment projects Prepared detailed study proposals for ethical review at the hospital | |

| | Leader of patient data collection team at Cho Ray Hospital in 2022 (Economic burden of lung cancer patients at Cho Ray Hospital) Oversaw the overall PAS compliance and coordination between the hospital, pharmaceutical companies, and regulatory bodies Managed patient enrollment and daily operations for the PAS at the hospital |
|--------------------------------|--|
| May 2021 – December 2021 | Health Economic - Math Modeling Intern |
| | Oxford University Clinical Research Unit, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam |
| | Wrote the research proposal Analyzed the panel data and evaluated the effect of Health Insurance Law on catastrophic health expenditure and impoverishment by causal inference methods Trained in writing a scientific paper by the supervisor |
| 2019 – 2022 | Research Assistant |
| | Department of Pharmaceutical Administration, University of Medicine And Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam |
| | Supported the mentors in fulfilling their theses: Health Technology Assessment of the two-stage ASP in HTD applying cost-effectiveness analysis and evaluating the long-term impact of the ASP by Simulation Modeling. |
| | Wrote scientific papers about Antimicrobial Resistance and ASP in the Hospital for Tropical Disease in HCM City |
| | Coordinated for the project named "Establishing essential metrics for ASP in hospitals" Project (QD709/QD-SKHCN) |
| | Conducted the surveys to evaluate the ASP activities in HCM hospitals as well as the practical and effective ASP metrics |
| | Involved in student assessment and supervision of undergraduate students for dissertation methodology |

Honours and Awards

Pharmacy Scholarship for Excellent Students (2017, 2018, 2019)

Third prize in iUMP competition (2020) (A competition searching and incubating creative, highly applicable ideas in the medical field)

Scholarship "STUDY TRIP TO KOREA" (2023) (A two-week trip to Korea to learn innovations and how to invest in new technology)

Books

Nguyen Thi Hai Yen, Nguyen Van Vinh Chau, Huynh Phuong Thao, Evaluation indicators for Antimicrobial Stewardship Program in hospitals, Publisher: Medical Publishing House, ISBN: 9786046661467 (**Co-author**)

Publications

Roles: † Study design; ‡ Data analysis; § Writing - original draft, review & editing

- Nhien Phan-Thuy Nguyen, Quynh Thuy Truong, Thao Phuong Huynh, Hien Thi-Thu Pham, Thanh Dinh Le, Yen Thi-Hai Nguyen, Nga Thi-Quynh Nguyen. Measurement of DDD and DOT metrics for optimizing antimicrobial surveillance in two tertiary hospitals in Viet Nam: a four-year retrospective study. Pharm Sci Asia 2024, See Article in Press †, ‡, §
- 2. Nga Thi-Quynh Nguyen, **Nhien Phan-Thuy Nguyen**, Quynh Thuy Truong, Thao Phuong Huynh, Minh Van Hoang, Yen Thi-Hai Nguyen. Increased costs associated with antimicrobial resistance at a tertiary hospital in Vietnam: a retrospective observational study from 2016 to 2021. Plos One (Under Review) †, ‡, §
- 3. Nguyen Thi Bich Nga, Ngo Ngoc Quang Minh, Nguyen Phan Thuy Nhien, Ngo Le Lan Uyen, Nguyen Thị Hai Yen, Nguyen Thị Quynh Nga. Analysis of direct healthcare costs in the treatment of community-acquired pneumonia at Children's Hospital 1 in 2022. Vietnam Medical Journal, 537. URL: https://tapchiyhocvietnam.vn/index.php/vmj/article/view/10198 †, ‡, §
- 4. Nguyen Thi Thuy Anh, Nguyen Phan Thuy Nhien, Tran Ngoc Thien Phu, Nguyen Thi Quynh Nga, Dang Thi Kieu Nga. Cost-effectiveness analysis of 2 g of cefazolin compared with 1 g of cefazolin as prophylactic antibiotics in cesarean section at the Mekong Maternity Hospital from 2021 to 2022. Journal of Health and Development Studies, DOI: https://doi.org/10.38148/JHDS.0801SKPT24-003 §

- 5. Truong Thuy Quynh, Huynh Phuong Thao, **Nguyen Phan Thuy Nhien**, Nguyen Van Vinh Chau, Nguyen Thi Hai Yen. Vancomycin therapeutic drug monitoring before and after applying the target AUC approach at Hospital for Tropical Diseases from 2020 to 2021. Vietnam Medical Journal, 534(1B). https://doi.org/10.51298/vmj.v534i1B.8273 §
- 6. Nguyen Thi Hai Yen, Le Dang Tu Nguyen, Tran Thi Hong Nguyen, **Nguyen Phan Thuy Nhien**, Do Van Dung, Nguyen Van Vinh Chau. Developing a set of assessment criteria for antibiotic stewardship program in hospitals. Vietnam Medical Journal, 525(1A). https://doi.org/10.51298/vmj.v525i1A.4986 †, ‡

Conferences and Seminars

- 1. Nguyen NT, **Nguyen NP**, Thai TT, Nguyen TD, Tran DT, Nguyen YT. Implementation of Health Technology Assessment in Vietnam: A Hybrid Policy Delphi-SWOT analysis. 4th ASEAN PharmNET 2024, June 2024, Bangkok, Thailand. See booklet of abstracts
- 2. Tam Huu Dang, Uyen Le Lan Ngo, **Nhien Phan-Thuy Nguyen**, Phu Ngoc-Thien Tran, Luyen Dinh Pham, Nga Thi-Kieu Dang, Analysis of Direct Medical Costs in Patients Undergoing Knee Joint Surgery at the Hospital for Traumatology and Orthopaedics in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, 4th ASEAN PharmNET 2024, June 2024, Bangkok, Thailand. See booklet of proceedings
- 3. **Nguyen Phan Thuy Nhien**, Nguyen Thi Hai Yen, Dang Thi Kieu Nga et al. (2024). Burden of some chronic diseases in Imic: An umbrella review, **Oral Presentation**, 40th Technical and Scientific Conference at University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City
- 4. **Nguyen NP**, Truong QT, Huynh TP, Pham HT, Le TD, Nguyen YT, Nguyen NT. Measurement of DDD and DOT Metrics for Optimizing Antimicrobial Surveillance in Two Tertiary Hospitals in Viet Nam: A Four-Year Retrospective Study. **Poster Presentation**, 4th Infectious Disease Society of Ho Chi Minh Conference: Advances in diagnosis and treatment of infectious diseases

Skills and Expertise

Languages:

Mother tongue: Vietnamese

Other languages: English (IELTS certificate: 6.5 – Reading: 6.5; Listening: 6.5; Writing: 6.0; Speaking: 6.0)

Technical Skills:

- Statistical analysis (R, STATA), product communication (R Markdown and Shiny), version control (GitHub): Advanced proficiency
- Economic evaluation using mathematical models (VBA and R programming): Advanced proficiency
- Conduct in-depth interviews, and focus group discussions using participatory tools: Intermediate proficiency
- Study design and digital data collection using SurveyMonkey and Microsoft Form: Intermediate proficiency
- Basic designing with Photoshop, familiar with designing communication materials such as brochures, posters, and flyers
- Microsoft Office (Word, Powerpoint, Excel): Professional proficiency

Personal Skills:

- Experience in communication with many stakeholders such as policymakers, researchers, hospital staffs and patients
- Familiar with leadership and teamwork to supervise project activities and support other members to fulfill their duties.

Certificates and Training

Improving your statistical inferences (2024):

Coursera Online Course - Eindhoven University of Technology

• ICH GCP (2022)

Ministry of Health (Vietnam)

Intermediate R-HTA Modelling (2022)

R for Health Technology Assessment (HTA) academic consortium

Practical Time Series Analysis (2021)

Coursera Online Course - The State University of New York

Antibiotic Stewardship Program (2021)

Online training - Medical and Pharmaceutical University Hospital in Ho Chi Minh City

References

Referee 1: Assoc.Prof.Dr Nguyen Thi Hai Yen

Vice Head, Pharmaceutical Administration Department, Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Medicine and Pharmacy at Ho Chi Minh City

E-mail: haiyen@ump.edu.vn

Referee 2: Dr. Ong The Due

Vice Head, Department of Health Financing and Health Technology Assessment, Health Strategy and Policy Institute in Vietnam

E-mail: ongthedue@hspi.org.vn Referee 3: Dr. Sayem Ahmed

Lecturer (Education) in Health Economics, London, UK

E-mail: sayem.ahmed@brunel.ac.uk